well let's get a move on then and ICI
Lombard in Focus as the company has
approved the merger of bti axa's
non-life insurance business let's find
out what exactly the details are of this
and what brokerages as well have to say
somia is standing by with the details
morning
[Music]
Sam while ICC Lombard is in Focus board
has approved the merger of bti exr's
General Insurance buiness business with
itself uh now let me give you a little
context bharti AA stands at and is
ranked at 70 when it comes to the
general insurance industry while on the
other hand IC Lombard holds fifth
position in the entire non life
insurance space well as for the press
release the combined entity would now
emerge as the third largest non-life
insurer in India well talking about the
shareholding pattern the promoter icic
Bank holds currently holds close to
about
51.9% stake in ic lmar while the rest is
held by the public with this proposed
deal taking place the promoter uh stake
would come down to 48.1% also bti and
AXA will com combinely hold uh 7.3%
stake apart from this um given the fact
that this transaction is through a
shares swb deal The Exchange R for the
same stands that two shares of ICS
General insurance for every 115 shares
held uh by shareholders of bti XA
General Insurance however uh in the
recent con call the analyst did raise
some concerns as far as valuations for
this deal is concerned to which uh the
company did try to assu concerns saying
that they believe that going forward
there significant Headroom for operating
leverage and cost Effectiveness over
time apart from this they do not require
any Capital raise as of now given for
solvency purposes given the solvency
solvency margins are well above
regulatory requirements let me also give
you a little brief about bti EXA that
predominantly are into motor insurance
and uh uh I s Lombard believes that
given this segment would uh they are pro
predominantly in this segment together
they would be able to command a higher
market share as far as motor insurance
is concerned uh well apart from this
they also add that the distribution uh
mix and the banker tyes of bhi EXA would
provide uh significant uh uh leverage to
the company going forward as far as the
overall distribution network is
concerned so in a whole given uh that
health insurance portly has gained a lot
of traction uh in the last last few
months General insurance industry as a
whole has been gaining a lot of traction
so with this uh merger taking place we
believe and the company also believes
that this would provide significant uh
impetus as far as growth is concerned